JOSEPH JOHNSON

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- +44 7512 610315 (UK)
- joseph.johnson27001@gmail .com
- Potton, Bedfordshire, UK
- joseph-johnson27001.github .io/Website/

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- React.IS
- Chart.js
- VueJS
- Vuex
- Vuetify
- Bootstrap
- JSON
- PostgreSQL
- SASS
- Typescript
- jQuery
- Node & Yarn Package Manager
- GitHub
- Wordpress
- Elementor Page Builder

EDUCATION

Front End Tech Degree

Team Treehouse

Remote | 2020

Ancient History

Royal Holloway: University of London Surrey, UK | 2013

PROFILE

An ambitious web developer, with a passion for creating clean, responsive and user-friendly websites. Along with my professional experience, I have developed a cryptocurrency tracking application, a quiz application and several other demo sites, all of which are viewable on my portfolio page. I now hope to join an exciting team where I can contribute to projects for clients, whilst continuing to broaden my programming knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR DEVELOPER

DIRECT BUSINESS SOLUTIONS | REMOTE | APR 2021 - JAN 2022

- Utilised 'Vue.JS' and 'Vuetify' to develop a scheduling application, with built-in reminders, timers, and notifications. This product was then used by the entire sales team to assist with the business' daily sales operation
- Linked the above scheduling application to 'Microsoft Outlook' and 'Microsoft Todo' through the use of an API
- Implemented a service worker in order for the sales team to use the above application offline
- Discussed with other members of the team how best to utilise UX and UI features for the staff website
- Edited staff website based on the developed designs
- Created editable data tables, with information drawn from back end databases, utilising both PostgreSQL and VueJS
- Completed various ad hoc coding tasks, including database management fixes, editing web page styling, and re-working programming functions
- Utilised the 'liveshare' feature on 'Visual Studio Code' in order to edit code with other team members
- Installed and updated needed dependencies, using both 'Node Package Manager' and 'Yarn'
- Engaged in code reviews with other members of the team

FREELANCE WORK

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Using JavaScript, developed a minimum viable product for an information security policy website
- Created a photography website using 'Wordpress,' the Divi theme and the Elementor page builder
- Liaised with customers about design aspects and provided suggestions based on their requirements
- Edited sites accordingly based on client feedback

JOSEPH JOHNSON

WFB DFVFI OPFR

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- ISO 27001 Lead Implementer
- ISO 27005 Risk Management
- 120 Hour TEFL Certification

LANGUAGES

- English | Fluent
- Mandarin | Basic
- French | Basic

INTERESTS

- Travel
- Music
- Football
- Photography
- Cooking
- Weightlifting
- Chess
- History
- Psychology
- Gaming
- Guitar
- Cryptocurrency
- Studying Mandarin

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

PERSONAL WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Built a cryptocurrency tracking webpage using multiple API's, ReactJS and Chart.js
- Created an online quiz application, using JavaScript programming, with multiple questions and categories for the viewer to choose from
- Developed a Star Wars Themed portfolio page for Darth Vader, based on designs found online
- Utilised 'Bootstrap' to create a landing page for an imitation tour company
- Developed a landing page for a "cliche" business company
- Built a mock employee directory, using JSON and an API
- Developed a mock web application dashboard utilising different interactive jQuery charts
- Built a JavaScript focused 'Star Wars' game based on the TV show, 'Wheel of Fortune'
- Used the SASS preprocessor, to develop a mock web style guide, which could then be used to help style projects
- Developed and created an online personal portfolio page using HTML & CSS,
 JavaScript, and the CSS framework 'Bootstrap', to host all of the above projects
- Completed the Team Treehouse 'Front End Web Development Techdegree' whilst receiving the highest marks of 'Exceeds Expectations' for every project

ONLINE ENGLISH TEACHER

ITUTORGROUP | REMOTE | AUG 2018 - APR 2020

- Provided Online English classes to Chinese and Japanese adult students
- Received an average rating of 9.8/10 across 1000+ teaching hours

OPERATIONS ADMINISTRATOR

CAMBRIDGE ASSESSMENT | CAMBRIDGE, UK | FEB 2018 - AUG 2018

- Assisted with the worldwide operational running of the IELTS language examination
- Worked closely with all levels of the IELTS hierarchy including students, test centres, assessment teams, and directors

ENGLISH TEACHER

AFFILIATED SCHOOLS OF THE BEIJING UNIVERSITY OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY \mid BEIJING, CHINA \mid FEB 2016 - JUL 2017

- Prepared and delivered English lessons to around 900 Chinese students aged 7-16
- Created bespoke lessons for each class and provided monthly reports for each student